978-995-8782 kellerkaren9@gmail.com kellerkaren9.github.io



360 Littleton Road, A15 Chelmsford, MA 01824

Artist. Designer. Educator.

I am an artist and art educator who values the hard work and interpersonal skills required to lead a classroom in advanced artistic activities. I plan to collaborate with fellow artists and the community to generate meaningful experiences through art.

## Education: GPA: 3.92

University of Massachusetts Dartmouth, Class of 2020 BFA in Art Education with a Concentration in Graphic Design 5-12 Visual Arts Teacher (Massachusetts License Pending) Chelmsford High School Class of 2016 Commonwealth Honors Scholar Chancellor's List (2016-2020)

# **Employment:**

Practicum at Dartmouth High School	Student Teacher (2020)  During student teaching taught Studio Art One, Graphic Design, and AP Portfolio to high school students. I provided artistic learning opportunities for a variety of situations and individual needs, adjusted my practice based on feedback and reflection, and connected with everyone in my classroom (and online during COVID19) to create a safe and encouraging learning environment.	
Multiliteracy & Communication Center	Tutor (2019-2020) As an MCC tutor, I worked one-on-one with students to guide their learning experiences with various class writing and presentation assignments.	
New England Yachad	Staff Member (2019) Intern (2018) Yachad is a non-profit organization which works toward engagement and inclusion services for people with disabilities. With New England Yachad, I taught art classes, designed informational and branding materials, completed various administrative tasks, and most importantly, engaged with adults with a variety of disabilities.	
America Reads	Tutor (2017-2018) As an America Reads tutor at Carney Academy, I assisted a first-grade classroom with learning, classroom behavior, and interpersonal skills.	

### **Specialized Skills:**

Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign, HTML, CSS, Traditional Painting, Digital Painting, Drawing, Teaching, Curriculum Design, Research, Communication and Writing.

### **Leadership Activities:**

Honors Council UMass Dartmouth	Creative Specialist and Paint Night Leader (2018-2020) Secretary (2016-2018)
Yearbook	Cover Artist & Artistic Editor (2015-2016)
Junior Cotillion Mural	Designer and Co-Leader (2015)

#### Awards:

Jennifer W. Mulnix University Honors Program Service Award (2019) Kyle Roy Scholarship (2019) Dante Vena Memorial Scholarship (2017) Chancellor Merit Scholarship (2016) Robello Art Scholarship (2016) Shirley Lavoie Memorial Art Scholarship of Chelmsford Art Society (2016) AP Scholar with Distinction (2016)

References: furnished upon request